<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Bass</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alex Bass</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Covid Email Update</title>
      <link>/projects/2021-10-22-covid-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2021-10-22-covid-update/</guid>
      <description>Intro (TL;DR I created a weekly COVID email update. Scroll to the bottom to opt-in🙂)
I’m excited to talk about this latest project🎉🎉
In the past few days, Europe has seen a third wave of COVID-19 surge through and several other countries are reporting higher cases this week (~10% increase!). All of this begs the question of whether COVID in the U.S. will have a third strong wave after the what we’ve seen from the delta variant and with winter coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Facebook Data... EXPOSED</title>
      <link>/post/facebook-exposed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/facebook-exposed/</guid>
      <description>Do you like the title? You can thank all of my click-bait ad consumption for that.
As some of you may know, my work is fairly political, so I have developed a habit of staying up to date on news and politics. Recently, social media has made some headlines including talks at congressional hearings, reporters expressing concern over its influence on elections, and some are worrying about censorship. So, amid all of this (and the rest of this post is a much lighter tone than this intro), I wanted to download my personal data from Facebook to show an overview of the role its played in my life since I got an account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me Hi! My name is Alex Bass. I work as an analyst at Morning Consult, a leading polling and market research firm. Also, I am a graduate student at the University of Virginia in Data Science.
Recently, I find myself doing data analysis and programming projects in my free time. I created this blog as a place to post some of these fun projects I work on off the clock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latter-Day Saints: Growing Pains In The GOP</title>
      <link>/post/2019-12-09-latter-day-saints-growing-pains-in-the-grand-old-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-12-09-latter-day-saints-growing-pains-in-the-grand-old-party/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Between Mitt Romney’s nomination in 2012 and present times, the Republican Party has seen shifts in make-up and goals. In 2016, Trump tapped into a somewhat different base than previous Republicans - appealing strongly to non-college whites. Policy-wise, Trump has been more aggressive with border-controls, pushing domestic production, and tougher on some foreign players like China. But, while some groups have been more supportive of the evolving GOP platform, others have drifted further from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting...My Election Model!</title>
      <link>/projects/election-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/election-model/</guid>
      <description>Last updated November 2, 2020
There are a lot of election models out there - the Economist, FiveThirtyEight, and the Cook Political Report to name a few. So what am I doing here?
The Problem Honestly, I was irritated in blindly trusting other’s models. Many election model builders claim to use demographic patterns, previous election results, economic considerations, polls, etc.. But, beside polling numbers, what data exactly are they using and where does it come from?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boiled Peanuts and Word Search Puzzles</title>
      <link>/projects/2020-07-31-boiled-peanuts-and-word-search-puzzles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/2020-07-31-boiled-peanuts-and-word-search-puzzles/</guid>
      <description>The genesis of this project came late night at a restaurant dinner in Charleston. I went out with my family to enjoy one of the delicious seafood locales common to the holy city. Going out with my family is always enjoyable with good conversation and lots of laughs. My parents enjoy taking our family out to eat now because my 4 siblings are mostly college-aged and can behave well in a public setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ford, Toyota, Honda? Who Takes the Cake?</title>
      <link>/post/2021-01-13-ford-toyota-honda-who-takes-the-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021-01-13-ford-toyota-honda-who-takes-the-cake/</guid>
      <description>A look into US car sales data in the last 25 years…
Introduction This project started out as me trying to recreate a moving bar chart. I saw them around online and thought they were a cool way to visualize data over time that reminded me of a “data race.” Ironically, I came across a great site that stores car sales data over time, and thought it was the perfect fit to create a “race chart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobility in the COVID-19 Era: Urban vs. Rural</title>
      <link>/post/2020-06-09-mobility-in-the-covid-19-era-urban-vs-rural/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-06-09-mobility-in-the-covid-19-era-urban-vs-rural/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this unprecedented time, America and the world have experienced drastic changes in many aspects of modern day life. In an effort to “flatten the curve” of the coronavirus, American leaders urged for precautionary measures such as closing non-essential businesses, stay-at-home orders, and general social distancing protocol across the country.
The coronavirus has plagued our nation for several months now. In this post, I aim to answer two questions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Feel free to shoot me an email here: acbass49@gmail.com
or ask me on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
